# **Lindsay Kinn**

Marietta, GA 30062 | 314-258-2144 | lindsay.kinn@gmail.com GitHub Profile | Blog | LinkedIn | CV

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming with a background in operations. A results-driven and creative Software Engineer with a vision to bridge the gap between developers and end users. 15+ years of experience in business analysis and process pivoting to web development. Able to identify requirements and priorities and resolve issues in initial stages.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby | Rails | SQL | JavaScript | React.js | Redux.js | Bootstrap | Git | Heroku | PostgreSQL | Oracle | Salesforce | Siebel

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

### Taste - Link to Project | Demo

A Ruby on Rails application for users to create and share recipes.

- Used Bcrypt to hash passwords ensuring user security.
- Utilized OAuth tokens to grant users access to the application via Google providing secure sessions.
- Capitalized on the Cocoon gem to implement dynamic nested forms for ease of user experience.
- Hosted application via PostgreSQL and Heroku to expand user reachability.
- Detailed object orientation through Ruby on Rails with full CRUD.

# Pokémon Application - Link to Project | Demo

A Sinatra-based application to keep a catalogue of a user's collected Pokémon cards.

- Applied the SQL language to facilitate data retrieval.
- Illustrated database table functionality through SQL.
- Incorporated the Sinatra framework to capitalize on the MVC structure.
- Demonstrated full CRUD & RESTful routing conventions.
- Required validations to ensure uniqueness of a user login attribute.

### Let's Taco Bout It! - Link to Project | Demo

A JavaScript SPA application to log and house favorite tacos.

- Object-oriented JavaScript providing a dynamic, easily interpreted developer experience.
- Used AJAX calls to create an asynchronous web application thus minimizing page response time.
- JSON operates as the communication format to transmit data, so it can be displayed on a web page.
- Client-side JavaScript uses `fetch` and the Rails API was shaped with RESTful conventions.
- Executed a "dark mode" feature using Bootstrap to reduce the light emitted by device screens while maintaining the minimum color contrast ratios required for readability.

### **EXPERIENCE**

**Momenta Tech** Remote

Freelance Web Development

06/2020 - present

- Worked with Senior JavaScript Developer to create over 200 calculators for Punchlist Zero: Energy Industry Education, Tools & Calculators
- Styled and published all conversion calculators using WordPress
- Calculators can be found at <u>Unit Conversion Calculator Convert Just About ANYTHING</u>

**Ingersoll Rand** Davidson, NC

Remote Monitoring Systems (RMS) Operations Analyst

01/2020 - 05/2020

- Collaborated with technical support groups to resolve device issues on the portal and in the field.
- Extracted/analyzed data from Tableau, Losant, and Siebel to measure Key Performance Indicators (KPIs).
- Developed Tableau MDI dashboard, in partnership with corporate training team, to interface with Siebel UI software and Oracle CRM.

Service Coordinator 08/2011 - 12/2018

**Relevant Solutions** Houston, TX Aftermarket Support Manager 01/2019 - 01/2020

Assisted IT team with ERP development adding features, including revenue/profitability gap reports, enhanced search capabilities, geo-locator to track technician location, and automated billing options to minimize redundancy.

- Saved \$6K/month and contributed to \$125K quoted revenue by evaluating processes, identifying cost-saving opportunities in travel entry/billing, and authored/rolled out training documentation to correct issues.
- Contributed to \$50K in monthly top line revenue by process review, recognizing improvements through repair delegation.

## **EDUCATION**

New York, NY Flatiron School Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program 11/2020 - 04/2021

Columbia, MO